Guide to the One Person, One Vote: Learning from the Past, Organizing for the Future, Voting Rights Conference Collection, 2015 September 18-20 RL.11120
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
One Person, One Vote: Learning from the Past, Organizing for the Future, Voting Rights Conference collection
2015 September 18-20
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
John Hope Franklin Research Center for African and African American History and Culture
RL.11120
0.2 Linear Feet 36 items
Collection comprises items related to the One Person, One Vote: Learning from the Past, Organizing for the Future Voting Rights Conference held September 18-20, 2015 in Durham, N.C. Materials include video of the proceedings, the conference program, contents of a participant notebook, feedback from attendees, and a mailing card for a related multimedia website.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The One Person, One Vote: Learning from the Past, Organizing for the Future, Voting Rights Conference collection was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2015.
Collection Overview
Collection comprises items related to the One Person, One Vote: Learning from the Past, Organizing for the Future Voting Rights Conference held September 18-20, 2015 in Durham, N.C. Materials include the conference program, contents of a participant notebook, feedback from attendees, and a mailing card for a related multimedia website.
Voting -- United States -- Congresses; Voting -- North Carolina -- Congresses; Voting -- Southern States -- Congresses.; Suffrage -- United States -- Congresses; African Americans -- Suffrage -- Congresses; Minorities -- Suffrage -- United States -- Congresses; African Americans -- Civil rights -- History -- 20th century; Voting Rights Conference. 2015: Durham, North Carolina; Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee (U.S.); Duke University. Center for Documentary Studies; John Hope Franklin Research Center for African and African American History and Culture
- Conference Video, 2015-09-18/2015-09-20; 1
  - Friday Opening Session, 2015-09-18; 1
    - OPOVConference_Video01_V6.mov, 02:41:45 (Digital-materials RL11120-SET-0001)
  - Opening Plenary: Putting the Question of Voting as a Constitutional Right on the Table, 2015-09-18; 2
    - OPOVConference_Video02_V5.mov, 01:38:14 (Digital-materials RL11120-SET-0001)
  - Cultural Work, Part 1: Setting the Tone, 2015-09-18; 3
    - OPOVConference_Video04_V2.mov, 01:25:20 (Digital-materials RL11120-SET-0001)
  - Saturday Opening Session, 2015-09-19; 4
    - OPOVConference_Video05_V2.mov, 01:12:49 (Digital-materials RL11120-SET-0001)
  - Plenary 2: How to Engage People In Asserting Their Right to Vote, 2015-09-19; 5
    - OPOVConference_Video06_V2.mov, 00:19:36 (Digital-materials RL11120-SET-0001)
  - Cultural Work, Part 2: Keeping Energy High, 2015-09-19; 6
    - OPOVConference_Video07_V2.mov, 01:34:45 (Digital-materials RL11120-SET-0001)
  - Plenary 3: How to Increase Voter Participation in the South (NC, MS, GA), 2015-09-19; 7
    - OPOVConference_Video08_V2.mov, 00:50:04 (Digital-materials RL11120-SET-0001)
  - Structural Change and Economic Justice, 2015-09-19; 8
    - OPOVConference_Video09_V2.mov, 00:29:33 (Digital-materials RL11120-SET-0001)
  - Workshop Report, 2015-09-19; 9
    - OPOVConference_Video10_V2.mov, 00:21:52 (Digital-materials RL11120-SET-0001)
  - Sunday Opening Session, 2015-09-20; 10
    - OPOVConference_Video11_V2.mov, 02:15:36 (Digital-materials RL11120-SET-0001)
  - Plenary 4: Learning From the Past, Organizing for the Future, 2015-09-20; 11
    - OPOVConference_Video12_V2.mov, 01:17:50 (Digital-materials RL11120-SET-0001)
- Other Conference Materials (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Materials include the conference program, contents of a participant notebook, feedback from attendees, and a mailing card for a related multimedia website.